
<!-- Note: this tip file is not actually used, the tip of the day
dialog has been disabled for the moment because I wasn't liking it
enough to take the trouble to finish the tips text... -->

<tips caption="Tip of the Day">
<tip>
<html>
<p><b>Welcome to Sonic Visualiser!</b></p> <p>Sonic Visualiser is a
complex application, but it's easy enough to get started with.</p>
<p>Try importing an audio file and using the Pane menu to add some
different views of it.</p> <p>Check out the links on the Help menu for
tutorials and other documentation!</p>
</html>
</tip>
<tip>
<html>
<p>Sonic Visualiser's window is organised into "panes" and
"layers".  To begin with, you have one pane.  Import an audio
file to see it displayed in a waveform layer on that pane.</p>
</html>
</tip>
<tip>
<html>
<p>Each pane can contain any number of layers, which appear stacked
from "front" to "back" on the same timeline.  A layer can contain a
view of audio, or of points (time instants) or data plots (time-values).</p>
</html>
</tip>
<tip>
<html>
<p>There's a "layer property box" to the right of each pane, with one
tab for each of the layers on that pane.  Click on a layer's tab to
bring that layer to the front.  You can then adjust its colour and
other display properties in the property box.

The first tab is always for the pane itself, which has a few
adjustable properties of its own.</p>
</html>
</tip>
<tip>
<html>
<p>If you have more than one pane, only one of them will be "current",
marked with a black bar at the left side.  Just click on another pane
to make it current.  Most editing operations affect the layer that's
at the front of the current pane.</p>
</html>
</tip>
<tip>
<html>
<p>You can use different zoom levels for different panes by un-checking
the Global Zoom control for one of them.  By default, all panes will
zoom and scroll together.</p>
</html>
</tip>
<tip>
<html>
<p>You can speed up and slow down playback using the Playback Speedup
control in the bottom-right of the window.</p>
</html>
</tip>
<tip>
<html>
<p>The Transforms menu lists things you can do to extract features from
or process your audio.  The available outputs of any Vamp
feature-extraction plugins or LADSPA audio effects plugins you have
will show up here.</p>
</html>
</tip>

</tips>


